--- PAGE 1 ---
Information Retrieval & NLP 
TripAdvisor Recommendation System 
First project 
 
Goal : Based on one or a set of reviews of one place, the system must recommend the most 
similar place. 
Hypothesis : In this work we made the hypothesis that similar experiences (restaurant, hotel, 
attraction) are expressed in a similar way. If this hypothesis is true, then we can recommend a 
similar experience relying only on reviews. 
Evaluation : Even if the system only relies on reviews, we need a way to evaluate our hypothesis. 
For a given experience, if the system recommends a similar one then the query and retrieve 
experience must share the same categories described on metadata. 
_______________________________________________________________ 
Data provided :  
Reviews are in reviews83325.csv. Each line is a review. 
Places information are in Tripadvisor.csv. Each line is a place with entire description. 
Places and reviews can be joined by idplace (in reviews) and id (from places). 
To simplify, you can use reviews that are only in English. You can filter with attribute ôlangueö . 
 
Difficulties : the number of reviews by places is variable. Reducing the discrepancy size 
between places can help. Different strategies are possible it can be by filtering reviews in order 
to keep only a given number. It can be by selecting only the best sentences or best words fixing 
also the size of the selection. For example, you can use Tf-idf to select the best 100 words that 
describes a placeà 
Evaluation : 
Level 1 evaluation :  the most simple level of evaluation is to check if the retrieved place is of the 
same type of the query place by checking the attribute typeR and to make an average of the good 
finding normalized by the number of recommendations. 
For typeR attribute, only 4 possibles outcomes are possible: H,R,A and AP for respectively Hotel, 
Restaurant, Attraction and Attraction Product. 
 
Level 2 evaluation :  
In order to have a more precise evaluation, other information is provided. 
For attractions : In tripAdvisor table, activiteSubCategorie attribute is a list of ids where definition is on 
table activiteSubCategorie. 
--- PAGE 2 ---
activiteSubType attribute is even more precise where definition is on table activiteSubType. 
 
For restaurants you can find the restaurantType and cuisine attributes. 
For hotels, you can use the priceRange attribute. 
Ranking Error metric :  
In order to evaluate your models, you need to random split places between train and test. You 
can keep 50% for train/queries and the other 50% for test. 
Since some metadata are very precise, we cannot suppose the perfection of the model. In order 
to have a more informative evaluation and not a binary one, we can return the position of the first 
similar place according to the metadata. 
Example :  
If the query place is an attraction, that is an art museum. Our system will rank every test places. 
If the first place retrieved is an art museum, the system has an error of 0 (itÆs a perfect 
recommendation). If itÆs not the case and we need to go to position 7 to find an art museum, the 
system have an error of 6 (n-1, because we start at zero). If it doesnÆt exist on test set any place 
with same metadata, then the query is not tested (error is undefined). 
You can use a ranking error of level 1 or of level 2. For the level 2 since some attributes are a list 
of several categories, we define as a positive match if at least one of the categories matches. 
For example if the query place is an art museum and a garden, if a retrieved place is only a 
garden, we consider that the recommendation matches the query. 
 
Warning : you can do what you want but any of the information used for evaluation canÆt be used 
to design your system that only relies on reviews. The metadata used to evaluate the model 
cannot be used in input of the model. 
 
Deliverables :  
1) In order to validate your pipeline, run the simple baseline bm25 on it : 
https://pypi.org/project/rank-bm25/ 
2) Design a model better than bm25 
3) Evaluate bm25 and your model with Ranking Error Level 1 and Level 2 
4) Describe your model in a small report. You need to explain the logic behind all your 
choices. Describe also the different results 
5) Deposit your code on DVO (it can be a jupyter notebook) 
6) If you tested different models, describe and evaluate all you did. It shows your 
dedication. 
The project can be done by group of 2 students. The deadline is 2 mars 2026. 
 
Good Luck! 
